Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES III. Publications, 1930-80
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES III. PUBLICATIONS
  - "If you Don't Want a Baby Every Year," Prepared Under Direction of Dr. M. Calderone 1963 (Box 95, Folder 15)
  - "If You're a Business Man, This Chart May Be the Shape of Your Future," Reprint, Forbes 1972 (Box 95, Folder 16)
  - Illegal Abortion as a Public Health Menace, by Mary S. Calderone, Reprint, A.J.P.H. 1960 (Box 95, Folder 17)
  - "Illegitimacy: Myths, Causes and Cures," A Family Planning Perspectives Special Feature 1971 (Box 95, Folder 18)
  - "Immediate Postcoital Test," A.J. Sobrero, M.D., J. MacLead, Ph.D., Reprint, Fertility and Sterility, 3/62 (Box 95, Folder 19)
  - "Implementing DHEW Policy on Family Planning and Population," selected excerpts from The Harkary Report, 3/68 (Box 95, Folder 20)
  - "Improving Fertility," From Consumers Union Report on Family Planning, Reprint 3/5/67 (Box 95, Folder 21)
  - International Planned Parenthood Directory: Family Planning Agencies, 10th Issue, Feb. 1964 (Box 95, Folder 22)
  - "Individualizing Nursing Care in Family Planning," By Elizabeth Arnold, Reprint, Nursing Outlook 1967 (Box 95, Folder 23)
  - Infertility, by Dr. Abraham Stone 1952 (Box 95, Folder 24)
  - "Infertility," Reprint, Dr. Abraham Stone 1947 (Box 95, Folder 25)
  - Infertility and Adoption, Two Papers By Verne Weed and Dr. Milton S. Godfried 1951-1953 (Box 95, Folder 26)
  - "Information for Workers," Campaign 1946 (Box 95, Folder 27)
  - "Information Service," 1940-1942 (Box 95, Folder 28)
  - "Inside the Population Problem," John Gunther, A Mtg. 1962 (Box 95, Folder 29)
  - Instruction Talks: Diaphragm, Foam Powder 1940 (Box 95, Folder 30)
  - Intercom: Foreign Policy Assn., World Population Crisis 1968 (Box 95, Folder 31)
  - "Intrauterine Contraception," By Gordon W. Perkin M.D., Reprint, Canadian Med. Assn. Journal 1966 (Box 95, Folder 32)
  - Intercom: Focus on World Population, Jan./Feb. 1964 (Box 95, Folder 33)
  - "Intramural Hospital Contraceptive Clinics," By Dr. Alan F. Guttmacher 1958 (Box 95, Folder 34)
  - "IUD: How it Works, Is it Moral?," by Rudolph H. Ehrensing, M.D., Reprint, Nat'l Catholic Reporter 1966 (Box 95, Folder 35)
  - Is Birth Control Now Legal?, Decision U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals 1936? (Box 95, Folder 36)
  - "It Is Not the Unborn Who Suffer But the Unwanted," undated (Box 95, Folder 37)
  - "It is Time to End the Birth Control Fight," Saturday Evening Post Reprint 1963 (Box 95, Folder 38)
  - "I've Been Tested for Sickle Cell Anemia. Have You?" [Lelia] Hall 1972 (Box 95, Folder 39)
  - "Japan Wants Birth Control," Margaret Sanger 1953 (Box 95, Folder 40)
  - "Johnny Takes a Wife," Revised 1957 (Box 95, Folder 41)
  - Johns Hopkins Magazine, "Birth Control, A Sensitive Subject Too Long Neglected," May 1963 (Box 95, Folder 42)
  - President Johnson's State of the Union Message, N.Y. Times "Ad," 2/2/65 (Box 95, Folder 43)
  - Journal of Contraception 1939 (Box 95, Folder 44)
  - "Labor and Population Control," Mark Starr, Reprint 1940 (Box 95, Folder 45)
  - "A Landmark Decision," By Joseph N. Bell, Reprint from Good Housekeeping Magazine 1973 (Box 95, Folder 46)
  - "Last Will and Testament," undated (Box 95, Folder 47)
  - "Latin America Turns to Family Planning," By Albert Q. Maisel, Reprint, Readers Digest, April 1964 (Box 95, Folder 48)
  - "La Tuberculosis y La Maternidad," undated (Box 95, Folder 49)
  - "Legal Abortion: A Guide for Women in the United States," by Dr.'s Langmyhr and Rogers 1970 (Box 95, Folder 50)
  - "Legal Abortion: How Safe? How Available? How Costly?," Reprint, Consumer's Report 1972 (Box 95, Folder 51)
  - "Legal Abortion in the United States, Facts and Highlights," 12/73 (Box 95, Folder 52)
  - "The Legal and Moral Status of Therapeutic Abortion," By Dr. Guttmacher, Reprint, Progress in Gynecology 1963 (Box 95, Folder 53)
  - Legal and Political Aspects of Population Control in the United States, by Alvah W. Sulloway 1960 (Box 95, Folder 54)
  - The Legal Status of Contraception 1937-1948 (Box 95, Folder 55)
  - "Legalized Abortion Credited with Some Health Advances," Reprint, Medical Tribune 1974 (Box 95, Folder 56)
  - "Let's End the War Over Birth Control," By Rev. J.A. O'Brien, Ave Maria Reprint 1963 (Box 95, Folder 57)
  - "Let's Take Birth Control Out of Politics," by Rev. John A. Obrien, Look 1961 (Box 95, Folder 58)
  - "Limitation of Human Reproduction," 1940 (Box 95, Folder 59)
  - George N. Lindsay's, "Closing the Gap," circa 1966 (Box 95, Folder 60)
  - List of Hospitals in U.S. with Over 1,000 Births per Year, with Family Planning Services, 1966 (Box 95, Folder 61)
  - List of PP Affiliates 1970-1979 (Box 95, Folder 62)
  - List of PP Affiliates 1960-1969 (Box 95, Folder 63)
  - Lists: Planned Parenthood Publications from 1970 (Box 95, Folder 64)
  - PPFA Lists: Selected Bibliography, Family Planning, Population, Related Subjects 1966 (Box 95, Folder 65)
  - Lists: Selected Publications About Planned Parenthood 1957-1964 (Box 95, Folder 66)
  - List of Professional Publications 1963-1966 (Box 95, Folder 67)
  - PPWP Lists: Reprints from Family Planning Perspectives 1974-1975 (Box 95, Folder 68)
  - Lists: Selected Publications About Planned Parenthood 1956-1957 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - List: Pamphlets on Sex Education 1964 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Literature Lists 1935-1955 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - List of Publications 1954 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - List of Publications 1953-1954 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Look Magazine, See, "World's Exploding Population," 1951 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Look, Reprint: Parenthood U.S.A. 1947 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Look Magazine, Picture Folio 1942 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - "Looking Ahead to Marriage and Parenthood," Virginia League for Planned Parenthood, undated (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - "Love in Marriage," Lena Levine, M.D. 1952 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - "Love and Sex," By Mary S. Calderone, M.D., Reprint, Redbook, Feb. 1964 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - "Low Down on Tuberculosis," 1941 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - "Making the Best Use of, 'The Visiting Fireman,'" 1954 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - "Manual of Procedure for the Integration of Pregnancy Spacing," By Robert E. Seibels, M.D. 1942 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - "Margaret Sanger: Back from India," By Mildred Gilman, Reprint, The Nation 1953 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - "Margaret Sanger Meets a Mother Superior," 1943 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Margaret Sanger: Mother of Birth Control, Reprint, Coronet, Mar. 1966 (Box 96, Folder 17)
  - Margaret Sanger Research Bureau 1943, 1945 (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Marriage Counsel, An Outline for Clergymen, 1st Printing, undated (Box 96, Folder 19)
  - "Marriage Counseling," Rev. W.E. Crane, Out of Print, undated (Box 96, Folder 20)
  - "Marriage Counseling and the Legal Profession," Stone, Reprint 1950 (Box 96, Folder 21)
  - "Marriage Counseling as a Clergyman Sees It," Rev. W.A. Simms 1945 (Box 96, Folder 22)
  - Marriage Counseling Section, Harriet Pilpel and T. Zavin 1953 (Box 96, Folder 23)
  - Marriage and Sexual Harmony, Oliver M. Butterfield 1951 (Box 96, Folder 24)
  - "Marriage and the Home," undated (Box 96, Folder 25)
  - "Maternal Health and Contraception," 1932 (Box 96, Folder 26)
  - "Maternal Mortality in South Carolina," Report of Committee on Maternal Welfare 1939-1941 (Box 96, Folder 27)
  - "Maternal Mortality in South Carolina," Report of Committee on Maternal Welfare 1934-1940 (Box 96, Folder 28)
  - "Maternal Mortality in South Carolina," Report of Committee on Maternal Welfare 1940-1941 (Box 96, Folder 29)
  - "Medical and Biological Aspects of Contraception," John Rock, M.D. 1943 (Box 96, Folder 30)
  - "Medical Indications for Contraceptive Advice," by Eric M. Matsner, Med. Dir., April 1938 (Box 96, Folder 31)
  - "Medical Indications for Contraceptive Counseling," Reprint, New York Academy of Medicine, April 1965 (Box 96, Folder 32)
  - "Medical Opinion on Birth Control," 1938 (Box 96, Folder 33)
  - "Medical and Social Aspects of B.C.," Reprint, Journal-Lancet, Kleegman, Sophia 1935, 1938 (Box 96, Folder 34)
  - Medical Tribune, "Guttmacher Reports on Visit to Cuban M.D. Meeting," Reprint 1966 (Box 96, Folder 35)
  - Medical World News, Subject Files? 1960-1961 (Box 96, Folder 36)
  - "Medicine's Responsibilities in the Birth Control Movement," 1925 (Box 96, Folder 37)
  - "Metodos Anticonceptivos," By Calderone, Guttmacher, Tietze and Sobrero 1963 (Box 96, Folder 38)
  - "Memos for Nurses," 1961-1963 (Box 96, Folder 39)
  - "Message on Population and Family Planning," Pres. Nixon, Reprint 1969 (Box 96, Folder 40)
  - Mendoza, Ofelia, "Hacia un Hagar Feliz," Out of Print, undated (Box 96, Folder 41)
  - "Menopause," 1955 (Box 96, Folder 42)
  - "Mental Health is a Family Affair," Public Affairs Pamphlet 1949 (Box 96, Folder 43)
  - "A Message to Mothers," 1935 (Box 96, Folder 44)
  - "A Method of Contraception without Diaphragm," Hunter, Darner, Gillam 1952 (Box 96, Folder 45)
  - Method of Testing Relative Spermicidal Effectiveness, Brown, Gamble, Out of Print 1940 (Box 96, Folder 46)
  - "The Methodist Church and Planned Parenthood," 1962 (Box 96, Folder 47)
  - "Methods of Contraception in the United States," Revised, Publication of Med. Comm. 1965-1966 (Box 96, Folder 48)
  - "Methods of Contraception in the U.S.A.," For Professional Use 1963-1965 (Box 96, Folder 49)
  - "Metodos Anticonceptivos Modernos," 1966 (Box 96, Folder 50)
  - "Methods of Contraception in the United States," Dr. G.L. Langmyhr and Dr. Geo. C. Denniston, Revised 1968 (Box 96, Folder 51)
  - "Metodo del Ritmo," 1963 (Box 96, Folder 52)
  - "Ministerial Counseling and Planned Parenthood," Burkhart,. undated (Box 96, Folder 53)
  - "Mobile Units in New York City," Reprint, Daily News, August 10, 1965 (Box 96, Folder 54)
  - "Modern Contraceptives: Their Values and Limitations," Philip Williams, M.D. 1940 (Box 96, Folder 55)
  - "Modern Medicine Demands Birth Control," 1936 (Box 96, Folder 56)
  - "Modern Methods of Birth Control," Revised 1973-1977 (Box 96, Folder 57)
  - "Modern Methods of Birth Control," Dr. Langmyhr and George Denniston, M.D., Revised 1965-1968 (Box 96, Folder 58)
  - "Modern Methods of Birth Control," Revised Edition 1961-1966 (Box 96, Folder 59)
  - "Moral Aspects of Birth Control," Federal Council of Churches 1938 (Box 96, Folder 60)
  - "The Morality of Birth Control: What the Major Faiths Say," Reprint, Together 1965 (Box 96, Folder 61)
  - "More Healthy Children Now," 1942 (Box 96, Folder 62)
  - The Mother of Birth Control, Margaret Sanger, Reprint, Coronet, March 1966 (Box 96, Folder 63)
  - "[The] Most Important Thing," undated (Box 96, Folder 64)
  - "The Most Important Thing in the World," Campaign 1938 (Box 96, Folder 65)
  - "Mother of Planned Parenthood," Readers Digest, Reprint 1951 (Box 96, Folder 66)
  - Movie Guide, undated (Box 96, Folder 67)
  - "Must Birth Control Divide Our Religions?" Redbook Magazine 1960 (Box 96, Folder 68)
  - "National Leaders Agree: PP Means Better Families," Negro Literature, undated (Box 96, Folder 69)
  - "A National Program to meet A National Need," undated (Box 96, Folder 70)
  - National Resources Planning Board, "After the War, Toward Security: Freedom from Want," 1942 (Box 96, Folder 71)
  - "The Nation's Strength," 1947 (Box 96, Folder 72)
  - "A Nation Wide Program to Strengthen Our Population," undated (Box 96, Folder 73)
  - Nation's Manpower Revolution, Hearings: Com. on Labor and Pub. Welfare, U.S. Senate, Oct. 28, 1963 (Box 96, Folder 74)
  - Nat'l Congress of Parents and Teachers, Family Planning Resolutions, Adopted 1966 (Box 96, Folder 75)
  - "Nearly Every Woman Gets It," 1975 (Box 96, Folder 76)
  - "Necessity of Repeated Examinations in Fitting of Contraceptive Diaphragms," Kavinoky, Nadina, M.D. 1943 (Box 96, Folder 77)
  - "Negro Fertility and Family Size Preference," from The Negro American, by F.S. Jaffe, Reprint, Houghton Mifflin Company 1966 (Box 96, Folder 78)
  - "[The] Negro, Poverty and Population," By Edwin C. Berry, Address Delivered at PP Conference, Milwaukee 1965 (Box 96, Folder 79)
  - "The Need for Family Planning," Gitta Meier 1961 (Box 96, Folder 80)
  - "Need for Birth Control," Revised Chapter from The Hygiene of Marriage 1938-1932, 1938 (Box 96, Folder 81)
  - "Neglected Field of Preventive Medicine," 1947 (Box 96, Folder 82)
  - "Negroes and Birth Control," Dubois, W.E.B. Ph.D. 1938 (Box 96, Folder 83)
  - "New Antifertility Factor," By Benjamin F. Sieve, Reprint from Science 1952 (Box 96, Folder 84)
  - "New Baby Is Born," Campaign 1949 (Box 96, Folder 85)
  - "The New Battle Over Birth Control," Albert Maisel, Reprint, Readers Digest 1963 (Box 96, Folder 86)
  - "New Case History on Birth Control Pills," Reprint, Saturday Evening Post 1962 (Box 96, Folder 87)
  - "The New Crusade," Wm. H. Draper, Jr., Speech, Washington, D.C. Mtg. 1963 (Box 96, Folder 88)
  - "New Generation," Jan. 1939 (Box 96, Folder 89)
  - "New Day Dawns," Birth Control 1937 (Box 96, Folder 90)
  - "New Facts About Birth Control," Dr. Alan F. Guttmacher and Joan Gould 1959 (Box 96, Folder 91)
  - News Items: Milwaukee and Texas, B.C., Anti-Poverty, Reprint, N.Y. Times 1965 (Box 96, Folder 92)
  - "New Hope for Childless Couples," 1972 (Box 96, Folder 93)
  - "New Hope for Childless Couples," By Dr. G. Langmyhr and Dr. Denniston and Dr. S. Kaufman 1968 (Box 96, Folder 94)
  - "New Hope for Childless Couples," Dr. A. Guttmacher, Pageant Magazine 1960, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 95)
  - "New Horizons in Infertility Research," 1952 (Box 96, Folder 96)
  - "New Public Relief and Birth Control," By James H.S. Bossard, PhD. 1934 (Box 96, Folder 97)
  - "The New York Abortion Story," 1972 (Box 96, Folder 98)
  - Next Step: "Full Steam Ahead," undated (Box 96, Folder 99)
  - "Next Step Forward," American Birth Control League 1934 (Box 96, Folder 100)
  - "19 Ways You Can Help," undated (Box 96, Folder 101)
  - "Nobody Wanted Jimmy," 1932? (Box 96, Folder 102)
  - "No Contribution Too Small to Help," 1938? (Box 96, Folder 103)
  - "North, South, East, West: Planned Parenthood is News," Campaign 1947 (Box 96, Folder 104)
  - "Note on Early History of Contraception in America," Hines, Norman, E. 1931-1937 (Box 96, Folder 105)
  - "[The] Nurse and Planned Parenthood," undated (Box 96, Folder 106)
  - "Nurse-Midwife in a Family Planning Clinic," By Shirley Okrent, R.N., CNM, Reprint, Bulletin American Col. Nurse Mid.-W. 1966 (Box 96, Folder 107)
  - Nursing Outlook, American Journal of Nursing 1964 (Box 96, Folder 108)
  - Oates, James F., (Speech), "The Businessman's Stake in the Population Problem," 1966 (Box 96, Folder 109)
  - "Occlusive Methods of Contraception," Stone, Hannah M., M.D. 1937 (Box 96, Folder 110)
  - "Of Course We Want Children in Our Town," Campaign Piece 1950 (Box 96, Folder 111)
  - Oliver Bird Lecture (Eighth) on Intrauterine Devices, By Dr. A.F. Guttmacher, Reprint, Aug. 1965 (Box 96, Folder 112)
  - "One Hundred Years of Birth Control, An Outline of Its History," 1927 (Box 96, Folder 113)
  - "One Hundred and Fifty Years of Birth Control," 1948 (Box 96, Folder 114)
  - One Thousand Organizations Endorse, List of Organizations Endorsing Birth Control, May 1936 (Box 96, Folder 115)
  - "On the Interval Between Successive Births and It's Effect on Survival of Infant, An Indirect Method of Study," By J. Yerushalmy 1945 (Box 96, Folder 116)
  - "Open End," David Susskind, Birth Control, Dr. Al. G. Guttmacher, undated (Box 96, Folder 117)
  - Optimum Population for the United States 1940 (Box 96, Folder 118)
  - "Options: A Study Guide to Population and the American Future," The Population Reference Bureau 1973 (Box 96, Folder 119)
  - "Oral Contraception," Post Graduate Medicine, Dr. A.F. Guttmacher, Reprint, Dec. 1962 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - "Oral Contraceptives," By Edward Tyler 1961 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - The Other America, By Michael Harrington 1965, 1966 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - "[The] Outline of Marriage," By Floyd Dell, undated (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - "Organization, Objectives, Services," 1942 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - "Our Human Resources," March 1941 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - "[An] Outline of Contraceptive Methods," By James F. Cooper 1930 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - "Our Irresponsible Birth Rate: Lincoln Day," Condensed, Reader's Digest, Nov. 1960 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - "Outline for Developing P.P. Educational Programs Among Parent and Teacher Associations," 1945 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - "Outline for a Course in P.P.," by Mary Antoinette Cannon 1944 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - "Overpopulation: World Problem," Reprint, Midwest Journal, William Vogt 1952 (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - "Overpopulation is a Sin," by Father Arthur McCormack, Reprint, undated (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - "Paradox of Birth Control," 1934 (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - "Para Ayudarle En Sus Planes Para Levantar su Familia," 1954 (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - "[The] Paraformaldehyde Content of Contraceptive Foam Powders and Cream," Shediovsky and Bodner 1938 (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - "Parent Problem," Addresses Delivered at the 26th Annual Meeting 1947 (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - "Parenthood: Its New Responsibilities," By Alice T. Day, Reprint, Smith Alumnae [Quarterly], Nov. 1964 (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - "Parenthood, U.S.A.," Look, Reprint 1942 (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - "Passing the Buck," Affiliates' Fund Raising Bulletin, Issue 1, Oct. 1955 (Box 97, Folder 19)
  - Pastoral Life, Reprint 1966 (Box 97, Folder 20)
  - Patient Level Pamphlets, undated (Box 97, Folder 21)
  - "The Peaceful Revolution," P.P.'s 50th Anniversary Conference, Symposium, October 1966 (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - The People Pack 1973, 1974 (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - The People Pack, Revised 1972 (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - The People Pack 1966? (Box 97, Folder 25)
  - "[The] People Problem," Prepared by the Muskogee County Dept. of Health, Columbus, Georgia, Reprint 1968 (Box 97, Folder 26)
  - "People Read About Planned Parenthood," undated (Box 97, Folder 27)
  - "Physiologic Control of Fertility," Paul Henshaw 1953 (Box 97, Folder 28)
  - "Physiology of Reproduction and It's Relation to Regulation of Fertility," By Warren O. Nelson, Feb. 1963 (Box 97, Folder 29)
  - Pictorial Statistics, undated (Box 97, Folder 30)
  - Pill: "Is the Pill the Answer," by Kenneth N. Anderson, Reprinted from Today's Health 1965 (Box 97, Folder 31)
  - "The Pill and Morality," By Andrew Hacker, Reprint, N.Y. Times 1965 (Box 97, Folder 32)
  - "The Pill is Safe," by Edward T. Tyler, M.D. with Roland H. Berg, reprint, Look 1970 (Box 97, Folder 33)
  - "The Pill: It's Benefits and Risks," By Drs. Guttmacher, Lane, Connell, and Gen. Draper, Abridged Testimony 1970 (Box 97, Folder 34)
  - "Now! Something Better than...'The Pill'?," By Winfield Best, McCall's 1965 (Box 97, Folder 35)
  - "Place of Child Spacing in an Industrial Hygiene Program," Eva F. Dodge, M.D. 1942 (Box 97, Folder 36)
  - "Place of Fertility Control in Public Health," By Regine K. Stix, M.D. 1946 (Box 97, Folder 37)
  - "Plan Your Children for Health and Happiness," 1957; 1964 (Box 97, Folder 38)
  - "Planned Family," by Eric M. Mastner, M.D., Reprinted from Parents' Magazine, undated (Box 97, Folder 39)
  - "Planned Parenthood," 1940-41, 1950 (Box 97, Folder 40)
  - Planned Parenthood, Fundraising Guide 1957 (Box 97, Folder 41)
  - "Planned Parenthood Answers the World Challenge," Sir Colville Deverell 1964 (Box 97, Folder 42)
  - Planned Parenthood Helps in Five Languages for 1964 World's Fair, 1964 (Box 97, Folder 43)
  - Planned Parenthood and the Businessman, Wachsmuth Studies 1955 (Box 97, Folder 44)
  - Planned Parenthood, "A Positive Program," 1953 (Box 97, Folder 45)
  - "Planned Parenthood," Reprint of Article in Annals, By David Loth 1950 (Box 97, Folder 46)
  - Planned Parenthood, "Freedom to Choose," 1968 (Box 97, Folder 47)
  - "P.P. as a Public Health Measure for Negro Race," By Dorothy B. Ferebee, M.D. 1942 (Box 97, Folder 48)
  - "Planned Parenthood Goes to Press," 1954 (Box 97, Folder 49)
  - "Planned Parenthood, It's Contribution to Family, Community and Nation," 1943? (Box 97, Folder 50)
  - Planned Parenthood, "1951 Facts and Figures," 1951-1952 (Box 97, Folder 51)
  - "Planned Parenthood: Leadership, Education, Program Service," 1948 (Box 97, Folder 52)
  - "Planned Parenthood Makes News," 1954 (Box 97, Folder 53)
  - "Planned Parenthood," By Eleanor Roseberry, Reprint, Practical Home Economics 1945 (Box 97, Folder 54)
  - "Planned Parenthood," By Mabel Travis Wood 1938? (Box 97, Folder 55)
  - Planned Parenthood Means Healthier Mothers, Babies, undated (Box 97, Folder 56)
  - "Planned Parenthood and the Modern Inquisition," David Loth, Reprint, Humanist 1947 (Box 97, Folder 57)
  - PPFA: "Objectives, Activities and Structure for the 1970's," undated (Box 97, Folder 58)
  - Planned Parenthood Press Kit 1954 (Box 97, Folder 59)
  - Planned Parenthood Press Campaign Kit 1953 (Box 97, Folder 60)
  - Planned Parenthood Publicity Kit 1968-69 (Box 97, Folder 61)
  - Planned Parenthood Publicity Kit 1967-68 (Box 97, Folder 62)
  - Planned Parenthood Publicity Kit 1966-67 (Box 97, Folder 63)
  - Planned Parenthood Publicity Kit 1965-66 (Box 97, Folder 64)
  - Planned Parenthood Review 1940 (Box 97, Folder 65)
  - "Sex vs. The Law," By H.F. Pilpel, Reprint, Harper's, January 1965 (Box 97, Folder 66)
  - "Planned Parenthood and Social Welfare," By R.H. Richardson, Tenn. Conf. on Soc. Welfare 1965 (Box 97, Folder 67)
  - "Planned Parenthood Today," 1952 (Box 97, Folder 68)
  - "Planned Parenthood and the War," undated (Box 97, Folder 69)
  - "Planned Parenthood: A Basic Human Right," 1967 (Box 97, Folder 70)
  - "Planned Parenthood, A Basic Human Right... Planned Children are Wanted Children... Help Parents Plan," undated (Box 97, Folder 71)
  - Planned Parenthood and the War on Poverty, Nov. 1964 (Box 97, Folder 72)
  - "Planned Parenthood's Commitment," 1971 (Box 97, Folder 73)
  - "Planned Parenthood... For the Children of Tomorrow," 1967 (Box 97, Folder 74)
  - "Planned Parenthood in Africa," 1967 (Box 97, Folder 75)
  - "Planned Parenthood in Asia," 1966-1967 (Box 97, Folder 76)
  - "Planned Parenthood in Latin America," 1967 (Box 97, Folder 77)
  - Planned Parenthood in Wartime, Campaign Literature 1943 (Box 97, Folder 78)
  - "Planned Parenthood Services in State Public Health Programs," 1962 (Box 97, Folder 79)
  - Planned Parenthood Spots for Radio Announcements 1963 (Box 97, Folder 80)
  - Planned Parenthood, "Your Questions Answered," 1950, 1956, 1958, 1963-64 (Box 97, Folder 81)
  - "Planning to Have a Baby?," undated (Box 97, Folder 82)
  - "Planned Parenthood Worker's Handbook," 1945? (Box 97, Folder 83)
  - "Planning Your Family," Public Affairs Pamphlet 1948 (Box 97, Folder 84)
  - "Plant Materials Used by Primitive Peoples to Affect Fertility," Reprinted from Science, May 1954 (Box 97, Folder 85)
  - Policy Statement on Population, Statement: APHA 92nd Meeting in N.Y. 1964 (Box 97, Folder 86)
  - "The Population Bomb Keeps Ticking," Campaign to Check Pop. Explosion 1966 (Box 97, Folder 87)
  - "Population Boom or Bust?" 1972 (Box 97, Folder 88)
  - "Population: Decision by Default," Speech, J.D. Rockefeller, 3rd, American Assn. University Women Convention 1963 (Box 97, Folder 89)
  - Population and Family Planning, Pres. Committee 1968 (Box 97, Folder 90)
  - Population and Human Progress, Christian A. Herter, A Mtg. 1962, 1964 (Box 97, Folder 91)
  - "Population and Man's Future," Wash. D.C., John Rock, May 1963 (Box 97, Folder 92)
  - "Population and Our Shrinking World," Adlai Stevenson, Talk, 16mm Film 1964 (Box 97, Folder 93)
  - "Population Bomb," by Hugh Moore 1959, undated (Box 97, Folder 94)
  - "Population Boom: Too Many Mouths to Feed," Reprint, Newsweek 1954 (Box 97, Folder 95)
  - Population Control and Conservation, undated (Box 97, Folder 96)